Guide to the WXDU Records, 1977-2001
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
WXDU records 1977-2001
University Archives, Duke University
WXDU (Radio station: Durham, N.C.).
0.5 Linear Feet 250 Items
WXDU, as a member of the Duke University Union, exists to inform, educate, and entertain both the students of Duke University and the surrounding community of Durham through quality progressive alternative radio programming. WXDU was founded in 1983 when former station WDUK-1600AM switched to a FM signal.
Collection contains public records files, including correspondence and other materials related to FCC matters, program guides, clippings, a DJ handbook, and other materials. Materials range in date from 1977-2001.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The WXDU Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1980, 1995-1996, 2001.
Historical Note
WXDU, a non-profit student run radio station, was founded in 1983 when former station WDUK-1600AM switched to a FM signal. Whereas WDUK broadcasts were limited by the Federal Communications Commissions (FCC) to a range that barely covered the Duke University campus the new FM station WXDU could broadcast throughout the entire Durham community as well as the Duke University campus. The mission statement of WXDU proclaims that, as a member of the Duke University Union, [it] exists to inform, educate, and entertain both the students of Duke University and the surrounding community of Durham through quality progressive alternative radio programming.
Collection Overview
Collection contains materials pertaining to FCC matters including correspondence, employment reports, insurance policies, license applications and renewal, public service announcements, program guides, and other materials concerning the operation of the station. Other materials include a DJ Handbook, April 2000, list of board members, announcements, flyers, and clippings. Materials span the dates of 1977-2001.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
College radio stations.
Radio broadcasting.
WXDU (Radio station: Durham, N.C.)
WXDU -- Handbooks, manuals, etc. - DJ Handbook, 2000.
Clippings.
Related Material
WDBS collection, 1949-1983.
University Archives. Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - WDUK, 1977-1983, undated (Box 1)
  - WXDU, Public File, 1995
  - FM Translator, public file, 1987-1995
  - License Renewal, public file, 1993; 1995
  - Public Service Announcements, public file, 1995-1996
  - Employment reports/Ownership reports, public file, 1988-1995
  - Insurance Information, public file, 1987
  - Miscellaneous FCC Communications, public folder, 1983; 1991-1995
  - Program Guides, public file, 1986-1995
  - Records (taken from WXDU website), 2001
  - DJ Handbook, 2000